if you crashed your shbg jingle single
digits before getting on trt but you
don't want to get off trt how do you
increase your SBG F you don't that's not
how it works uh because then you're
artificially manipulating it you're not
letting the body do what it needs to do
to get that shpg back to where it wants
to be or needs to be if you've crashed
it then removing whatever crashed it and
giving things time is the best thing to
do this this desire I see this all the
time in groups and stuff this shbg topic
has become so huge you know Justin and I
did a little interview and uh we talked
about that um but this desire to
artificially uh alter your markers it's
just kind of it's misguided in the in
the thinking part of it because it's no
different than artificially reducing
your hematocrit by dumping blood it's
not a natural thing you're doing so
you're you're actually creating more
issues by pushing the body in that
direction quickly um just like over
dumping blood is going to actually
stimulate arthr poesis over time you
know because the body's
overcompensating um you know people look
at shpg and they'll take Boron to lower
it and they'll you know increase their
carbs to lower it go on a keto diet to
raise it yeah that's fine but if you're
not going to stick with that long term
what's the point of doing that for the
short-term gain because it's just going
to go back if you crashed it there's a
reason it crashed and so by removing
that cause you should be fine over time